exploretrending.com 2018-12-17

# Privacy Policy - Explore Trending

**Who we are**

_The site you are visiting is owned and operated by thiswebsite . Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At this website , we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we/our partners/ advertising companies gather and how this information is used._

**What personal data we collect and why we collect it**

We use third party email marketing services such as Mailchimp and Getresponse the details of data collected are as following.

**Getresponse**

When you sign-up using getresponse two types of information are collected including 1: Website use information and cookies 2: Personal information which you knowingly disclose in sign-up form including email address, physical address, name and telephone number. This information is used for sending future communications and newsletters as mentioned in sign-up form. Further details of user data protection and erasure of data can be found at this [link](https://www.getresponse.com/legal/privacy.html).

**Log Files**

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Contact Forms**

Our website uses third party contact form service “wpform” in contact us page. When you fill contact form certain data is collected including name, email address, website and phone number. All of this data is solely used to reply to user’s query; this data is not used for marketing purposes. Full disclosure of privacy by wpforms is stated [here](https://wpforms.com/privacy-policy/).

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

**In House Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**Third Party Cookies**

We also use third party advertisements on to support this site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

Third party vendors like Google use Cookies to display ads based on users prior visit to this site

**DoubleClick DART cookies**

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting:  
<http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/>

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

### **Google advertising cookies**

Google advertisement cookies will record users data such as age, sex and other demographics data.

To opt out from this you can use this [link.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

### **Embedded Content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Analytics**

This website uses multiple third party analytics services including jetpack and google analytics. Certain data is saved as general not traceable individually for generating trends. Full disclosure of privacy by google analytics can be found [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Similarly data is collected by jetpack’s service wordpress.com stats for analysis purposes including ip address, wordpress.com username if logged-in, user agent, visiting url, referring url, timestamp, browser language and country code, full details of privacy for this service can be found [here](https://jetpack.com/support/wordpress-com-stats/#privacy).

**Who we share your data with**

We don’t share your data with any party; however certain data is gathered by third party services when you visit our site details of which were mentioned in above paragraphs.

**How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. For the rights of data retained by third party services you should visit their respective privacy pages which are mentioned in above paragraphs.

**Where we send your data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

**Usage tracking**

We track user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. Statistics are broken down according to a user’s domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user’s browser).

We track and catalogs the search terms that a user enters in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.

**Children**

We will never request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18 without requesting parental consent.

**Use of Information**

We act upon information supplied to us voluntarily by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. We never share newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners.

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don’t track which terms a particular user enters.

We create aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don’t track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

**SHARING OF THE INFORMATION**

We use the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience’s demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

**SECURITY/DATA BREACH PROCEDURES**

We operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers. For details of Data breach procedures at third party services visit their respective privacy pages.

**YOUR CONSENT/CONTACT INFORMATION**

By using our sites, you consent to the collection and use of this information. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. For any query you can contact us.

If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of  then you may contact us at contact page.

## Opting in and out of communications made easy

Sometimes people want to read privacy notices because a business is asking for their permission to contact them for marketing. They want to be sure that, if they agree, it will be easy for them to withdraw permission in the future. We want you to be able to opt out as easily as you opted in. Any marketing email we send you will always have an “unsubscribe” link that will take you off that relevant marketing list. Please remember that you may have subscribed from another email address; you will only be able to use the link to “unsubscribe” from the address to which the marketing email has been sent. We make it easy for you to change your preferences for postal marketing as well, giving clear instructions for opting out on all direct mail.

* * *

## 1\. What personal information do we collect from you?

We collect information:

  * when you pay for any of our products or services
  * when you register to receive one of our newsletters
  * when you use any of our websites
  * when you attend any of our events
  * if you participate in any research we undertake
  * if you join one of our communities or forums
  * when you enter a competition
  * if you contact us about a query or a complaint

We collect the following types of information:

### Contact information

When you use or subscribe to one of our services, such as purchasing a print or digital subscription, signing up to an email newsletter, entering a competition, joining one of our online communities or participating in any of our research projects, we will ask you to provide information such as your name, email and/or postal address so that we can provide you with the services requested.

### General personal information

When conducting surveys or running competitions, in addition to contact information, we may collect other personal information such as your gender, date of birth, marital status, etc.

### Payment details

When you purchase a product or service from us, such as subscribing to one of our magazines or attending one of our events, we will also ask you for your payment details in addition to your contact information, in order to secure payment and to authorise access to our products and services.

### Online identifiers

When you visit one of our websites, we collect information about your web visit, such as how long you visited, what sites you visited or pages you looked at, your IP address and where you were when you visited, what sort of device you were using when you visited (such as a mobile phone or type of desktop PC, Mac etc).

### Behavioural data

When you visit one of our websites, we collect data on your online behaviour (eg time spent on website, items clicked on, etc).

When you buy a product or service from us, such as magazine subscription or a ticket to a this website  event, we will collect information about what products and services you have bought from us.

When you register for a newsletter or take part in research, we may collect data about your preferences, tastes and interests.

### “Special” categories of data

Sometimes, we may collect data in online surveys on what is called “special categories of data”. These could be data sets such as biometric information (including voice samples, facial recognition, etc), or political opinions, religion, philosophical beliefs, health, sexual orientation, etc. Whenever we conduct research on these topics, it is always optional, and we will make sure we have your consent to process this data. We will remind you at the time of why and how we are processing this data and what additional safeguards are in place for using, storing and ultimately either deleting or anonymising this data.

* * *

## 2\. How do we use your personal information?

At this website we collect different types of information about people for four main reasons:

  1. To provide personalised services unique to individual users.
  2. So we can monitor and improve the services we offer.
  3. To sell advertising space on our websites. This helps us to keep our websites free for people who visit them.
  4. To market products and services which we think would be relevant to you.

### Newsletters

When you sign up to one of our newsletters, you are giving consent for us to use the email address provided to send you relevant content for the brands you have signed up to. You can withdraw this consent for any newsletter by unsubscribing at any time.

### Advertising

We advertise on our site and in our newsletters to help keep most of the content free. We use cookies and similar technologies and work with trusted partners so that we can show you advertisements we believe might interest you, to control the number of times you see an ad and to measure the effectiveness of a campaign. We have a legitimate interest in using cookies but you can opt in or out of using them at any time. If you are interested and want to learn more about these, including how to opt out, please see our [Cookie Policy](http://hairstyles2019.com/cookie-policy/). Please note, opting out of cookies does not mean you will not see any advertisements.

### 

We work with social media networks such as Facebook Pixel to show you interest-based marketing content from our brands and selected advertisers if you have viewed a this website. Data collected by the Facebook Pixel may also be anonymised and used in aggregate to help improve the quality and effectiveness of our websites and marketing efforts.

You can limit the kind of tracking and profiling that Facebook undertakes by going to your Facebook account settings. You can also find out more about the pixels and cookies we use on our websites by reading our Cookies policy.

### Research & Insight

We run various user communities, forums and reader panels. We send out research invitations to our research communities, to people who pay for our products and services and to people who have opted in to receive communications from us.

### Delivery of goods and services / Customer account management

We will use the information you have provided for the provision of goods and/or services that you have requested and subsequently communicating with you about those products and services.

Please note too, that when you buy something from us – such as subscription or a ticket to an event – we may contact you about your registration details, to manage any account or subscription you have with us, or to provide customer service. This will be the case even if you have opted-out of, or declined to consent to, receiving promotional emails.

### Competitions

When you enter one of our online competitions, we will process your information for the purposes of picking a winner. If you have opted-in to receiving information from us about our products and services (eg receiving subscriptions offers, event invitations, signing up for editorial newsletters etc) then we will use the information you provide to make sure we offer you relevant products and services (based on where you live, your age, gender, tastes, preferences etc). If you have opted-in to receive news and offers from any competition sponsors, we will share your information with them.

Further details about this is outlined in the “who do we share information with” with section.

### Partnerships programmes

We work with our partners from the world of luxury goods, fashion, travel and retail so that we can present you with some outstanding offers and opportunities by either email or post. You will only ever receive partner messages from us if you have actively given permission. We won’t disclose your personal information to anyone, the messages will come from us and you can unsubscribe at any time from these messages.

### Customer queries and complaints

We process any information you provide when dealing with any complaints or enquiries made by you or legally on your behalf.

* * *

## 3\. Legal bases for data processing – what does it mean and how do we use them?

The law on data protection sets out several different reasons why a company may collect and process your personal data and it is one of our duties to make sure you understand which of these lawful bases we are using to process your data.

### Consent

In specific situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent. For example, when you tick a box to receive email newsletters.

### Contractual obligations

In certain circumstances, we need your personal data to comply with our contractual obligations.

For example, when you purchase a print subscription to a magazine, we will keep your name and address to fulfil your subscription.

### Legal compliance

If the law requires us to, we may need to collect and process your data.

For example, we can pass on details of people involved in fraud or other criminal activity affecting us to law enforcement.

### Legitimate interest

In specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests.

For example, we personalise the marketing content we provide you.

We will also use your address details to send you direct marketing information by post, telling you about products and services that we think might interest you.

* * *

### this website International and its subsidiaries

We may share your personal information:

  * If all or any of our assets (eg a title owned by us) were to be sold to another business, the personal data relating to that title (eg the subscriber list / newsletter list etc) would be transferred to the new business owner.

### Service providers

We work with service providers to perform some tasks on our behalf. This might include: analysis, payments, marketing, etc, and we may share your personal data with these providers to perform the necessary tasks. However, they are obliged not to disclose or use it for any other purposes. Any third-party processing of your data on our behalf will be subject to security and confidentiality obligations consistent with this privacy notice and applicable law.

### Customer research & insight

We may disclose de-personalised data (such as aggregated statistics) about the audience of our products and services and/or research participants to describe our sales, customers, traffic patterns and other information to prospective partners, advertisers, investors and other reputable third parties, and for other lawful purposes. These statistics will never include identifiable personal information.

### Law enforcement organisations

Under certain circumstances we may occasionally be required by law, court order or governmental authority to disclose certain types of personal information and we reserve the right to comply with any such legally binding request.

### Marketing partners

With your explicit permission, we may share your information with other companies we are working with, such as competition sponsors. Whenever we share your information with another company, we will always ask for your permission, will name the company and will always be clear that your information will be shared with another organisation.

* * *

## 5\. Collecting data on children

We do not knowingly collect and process information from children (anyone under the age of 13). The products and services we offer are generally aimed at people aged 18 and over.

If you are under the age of 13, we ask that you do not give us any information about you or use our websites.

If you are a parent or guardian of a child under 13 and you if you think that your child has used our websites or subscribed to a newsletter or provided their information to us without your consent, please contact us and we will delete and/or stop processing your child’s personal information within a reasonable time.

If you are aged between 13 and 18, we request that you seek your parent or guardian’s permission before providing us with your information or using our websites or apps.

* * *

## 6\. How long will we keep data?

We will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide the individual service/s you have requested, while taking into account any legal requirements and tax and accounting rules.

Where you sign up to receive email marketing from us we will retain your e-mail address after you ‘opt-out’ of receiving emails to ensure that we continue to honour and respect that request. To unsubscribe from marketing emails at any time, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any marketing email and update your account preferences. You may also use our preference centre to update what postal or email communications you wish you receive from us.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see ‘Your rights’ below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

* * *

## 7\. Profiling

We may sometimes use the data you share with us, and that we collect about you when browsing our websites and products, to personalise our services and to tailor marketing content. For example, we may use information you have provided to send you information about products we think you may be interested in. If you do not want to receive this material, you can unsubscribe at any point.

* * *

## 8\. Cross-border transfers and security

We make sure that we have appropriate security measures to protect your information and make sure that, when we ask another organisation to provide a service for us, they have appropriate security measures and follow the same high standards of security and data protection as we do.

If we or our service providers transfer any information out of the European Economic Area (EEA), it will only be done with the relevant protection (stated under UK law) being in place.

* * *

## 9\. Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to this website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on any other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you have accessed them using links from our websites.

* * *

## 10\. Your rights

As a consumer, you have rights when it comes to your data:

  1. **The right to be informed.**  At every point where we are collecting your data, we will inform you of why it is being collected and how it is being processed.
  2. **The right of access.**  If you wish to see what information we hold on you, you may send us what is called a Subject Access request. We will require photocopies of two pieces of identification. We will respond within 30 days of receipt of your request. There is no cost to you in requesting to see your data, but please note that we reserve the right to charge you if you make subsequent requests. You can use the contact details below for a Subject Access Request.
  3. **The right to rectification.**  We offer the opportunity to amend your personal information by contacting us using the details below.
  4. **The right to erasure.**  If you wish to cancel all communications with us, we can anonymise or de-identify your data. Please contact us using the details below. Please make sure you inform us of  **all** email accounts, profiles, names etc that you may have used with us that you wish to erase.
  5. **The right to restrict processing.**  You can opt-out or restrict the processing of your data by: 
    * Amending your cookie settings in your browser
    * Unsubscribing from postal and email communications, using our preference centre

If you are unhappy with the way we have collected and are using your personal data please do not hesitate to contact us, using the contact details below.

This policy outlines what cookies and similar tracking technologies our websites use, how we use them and information on how to opt out of these cookies if you wish to do so.

* * *

## Contents

  1. What are cookies?
  2. Why do we use them?
  3. What cookies do we use?
  4. Opting out of cookies

### What are cookies?

Cookies and similar tracking technologies, such as tags, scripts and beacons, are small pieces of code (referred to as cookies hereafter) that are stored on a device (computer, mobile phone, tablet etc) and enable a website can “personalise” itself to users by remembering information about the user’s visit to the website. We also use cookies within emails we may send.

Cookies are used to collect information, where available, about your device, your IP address, operating system and browser type and how you have interacted with our websites.

While cookies are used to identify users and devices, they only ever collect non-personal information such as IP addresses, device IDs. If the data cookies collect are ever merged with any other information with which you have provided us, such as email addresses, these are anonymised in such a way that identification to actual people is impossible.

* * *

### Why do we use them?

Our Websites use cookies to:

  * Store any preferences you have made and display content to you in a more personalised way
  * Evaluate our websites’ advertising and promotional effectiveness
  * Gain insight into the nature of our audience so we can tailor our content accordingly
  * Provide interest-based advertising on our websites and on other websites which are tailored to your interests and preferences

We have a legitimate interest to use cookies so that we can show you adverts we believe you might be interested in, to control the number of times you see an advert and to measure the effectiveness of a campaign. We advertise on our site and in our newsletters to help keep the content free for our audiences.

We will always make sure our websites contain clear and easy to find information about our cookies.

### What types of cookies do we use?

  * Per-session cookies – We only use these while you are visiting our website and they are deleted when you leave. They remember you as you move between pages, for example recording the items you add to an online shopping basket. They also help maintain security.
  * Persistent cookies – These cookies stay on your computer until they expire or are deleted. We set automatic deletion dates so that we don’t keep your information for longer than we need to.
  * First and third-party cookies – Whether a cookie is ‘first’ or ‘third’ party refers to the website or domain placing the cookie. First party cookies in basic terms are cookies set by a website visited by the user – the website displayed in the URL window. Third party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than the one being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and a separate company sets a cookie through that website this would be a third-party cookie.

Below is a full list of all different third-party cookies that we use:

Cookie | Type | Description  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics, Google AdSense, DoubleClick | Site analytics (Google Analytics) | Google ([www.google.com](https://www.condenast.co.uk/cookie-notice/www.google.com)) operates the Google Display Network: a collection of millions of websites and mobile applications that are powered by display advertising, including many Google services like YouTube. Google also operates the DoubleClick digital advertising platform: the ad technology foundation to create, transact, and manage digital advertising for the world’s buyers, creators, and sellers. The DoubleClick platform includes the DoubleClick Advertising Exchange and Double Click Bid Manager. To learn more about how Google collect and use information for online advertising, please visit <http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html>  
NetRatings SiteCensus | Site analytics | Nielsen Site Census is a browser-based audience measurement tool that provides in-depth tracking and analysis of our Web site users, site performance and other critical measurement data. Privacy Policy: <http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/privacy-policy/digital-measurement.html>  
Rubicon | Advertising | Rubicon Project is a leading technology company automating the buying and selling of advertising. Rubicon Project has engineered one of the largest real-time cloud and Big Data computing systems, processing trillions of transactions within milliseconds each month. The company’s technology created a new model for the advertising industry. Rubicon Project’s automated advertising platform is used by the world’s leading publishers and applications to transact with top brands around the globe. See more at: <http://rubiconproject.com/whoweare/#sthash.lysxULOn.dpuf>  
Oracle BlueKai | Advertising | The Oracle DMP creates profiles through the use of cookies, cross-device/cross-context technology (such as statistical IDs), or other unique identifiers provided to us by customers (such as mobile-device IDs) to learn about your journey across websites owned and operated by Condé Nast. This information is used in order to help us show you more relevant marketing content. To learn more about this cookie please visit Oracle BlueKai’s privacy policy (<https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy.html>) or to opt out please visit the Oracle BlueKai registry  
Full Circle Studies / Scorecard Research Beacon | Third party, advertising | Full Circle Studies is a market research company that studies Internet trends and behaviour. They work in conjunction with distributors and content providers to develop an anonymous, census-level analytics. For further information including how to opt out, please visit: <http://www.fullcirclestudies.com/privacy.aspx>  
Sizmek | Third party, advertising | Sizmek fuels digital advertising campaigns for advertisers and agencies around the world with the most cutting-edge technology to engage audiences across any screen. <http://www.sizmek.com/privacy-policy/>  
Facebook Pixel | Advertising | Condé Nast uses Facebook technologies such as the Facebook Pixel to show you interest-based marketing content from our brands and selected advertisers if you have viewed a Condé Nast website. Data collected by the Facebook Pixel may also be anonymised and used in aggregate to help improve the quality and effectiveness of our websites and marketing efforts. You can find out more about Facebook Advertising and manage your Facebook Advertising settings or opt-out of Facebook interest-based advertising at <https://www.facebook.com/ads/about/>  
Celtra | Audio/visual player | Celtra provides a web based self-service platform for creation, ad trafficking, tracking and optimization of rich media mobile display advertising. <http://www.celtra.com/privacy-policy>  
Adobe Typekit | Essential | Adobe Typekit puts a wide range of inspiring fonts within reach of all the tools you use to get your work done each day, so you can use great type in your projects without a second thought. <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/policies/typekit.html>  
Communities and forum site cookies / Vision Critical | Communities domains e.g. uk.voguevoices.com | Condé Nast uses Vision Critical as a provider of communities and forums. Vision Critical sets various cookies to administer the community websites. View the full list of [Vision Critical cookies](https://www.condenast.co.uk/privacy/vision-critical-cookies/).  
Twitter Share Button | twitter.com | When you create or log in to an account on [http://www.twitter.com](http://www.twitter.com/) cookies are stored on your computer in order to remain logged-in to your twitter account when visiting [http://www.twitter.com](http://www.twitter.com/) again. The Twitter Share Button used on our Website is hosted by [http://www.twitter.com](http://www.twitter.com/) and your browser therefore sends this cookie data to Twitter when creating the button inside your browser. This data is used by Twitter in order to associate the Twitter Share Button with your Twitter account. Please note that this data is not accessible to us, and is not sent to us by Twitter.More information about this cookie and Twitter’s Privacy Policy can be found at [http://www.twitter.com/privacy](https://twitter.com/privacy)  
Hotjar | Site analytics | Hotjar is a new all-in-one Analysis and Feedback tool that reveals the online behaviour and feedback of a website’s visitors. <http://www.hotjar.com/privacy>  
Pinterest | Social media | Pinterest lets you organize and share all the things you find on the web. People use pinboards to plan their weddings, decorate their homes, and organize their favourite recipes. <http://pinterest.com/about/privacy/>  
Facebook Connect | Social media | Facebook Developers is a social media platform that allows Facebook users to create Social Plugins, Graph APIs, and Social Channels, that enables websites to provide engaging social experiences to their users. <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>  
  
### Opting out of cookies

We provide you with choice over the use of cookies as described in this policy.

Please note that our websites may not work correctly if you change certain preferences, such as disabling all cookies.

Please also note that after applying these settings, you will continue to receive advertising, although it may not be tailored to your likely interests using information collected from cookies and similar technologies on your device.

**First Party Cookies.**  If you’d rather we didn’t use cookies when you visit us, click [here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/clear-cookies-installed.html) for information on how to configure your browser settings to reject cookies. Please note, disabling these types of cookies won’t turn off advertising on our websites and the advertising you see may be less relevant to you.

**Third Party Cookies.**  If you would like to opt-out of third-party cookies, here are some options:

  * If you would like to opt-out of receiving personalised ads from third party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), or who follow the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising, you can by visiting the opt-out pages on the [NAI website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) and [DAA website](https://digitaladvertisingalliance.org/) or click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) to opt out.
  * Google provides a suite of tools to control its cookies: 
    * Google Analytics, which is a tool used to track and report website traffic, provides an out-out browser add-on that can be downloaded [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
    * Google Safety Centre has a tool where you can control the ads you see on Google and control the data used for serving ads to you. It can be found [here](https://www.google.com/safetycenter/tools/#!/).
  * If you wish to block other cookies, including those being served by companies that are not part of the NAI or the DAA you can use the browser-level cookie controls described below.

### Browser-level cookie controls

Most browsers allow you to manage cookie settings. These settings can usually be found in the ‘Settings’, ‘Options’ or ‘Preferences’ menu of your browser. The links below are provided to help you find the settings for some common browsers.

  * Manage cookie settings in [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en) and [Chrome Android](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&hl=en) and [Chrome iOS](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DiOS&hl=en)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Microsoft Edge](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US) and [Safari iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265)

* * *

Thank you for reading our Privacy Policy. If you would like to contact us to understand more about our privacy policy or wish to contact us concerning any matter relating to individual rights and your personal information.
